module.exports = [
  {
    question: "Hello Hi there Welcome Greetings Hey",
    answer: "Hello User !! How can I assist you today?"
  },
  {
    question: "Bye thank you thanks",
    answer: "I hope I was able to answer you questions and clear your queries!!"
  },
  {
    question: "What is Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University is a non-profit educational institution located in Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India. It was founded by Ahmedabad Education Society (AES) more than 86 years ago."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of Ahmedabad University  ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University is dedicated to fostering continuous progress of self and society, becoming an exemplar in the transformation of higher education and research in India, and producing graduates with the capabilities, attitude, and values to excel in whatever field they choose to pursue around the world.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the mission of Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The mission of Ahmedabad University is to prepare leaders of outstanding character who will contribute significantly to their fields of study and practice, build an evolving learning environment based on cross-disciplinary linkages between the arts, sciences, and professional disciplines, actively advance research and intellectual enterprise at the University and in society, promote independent-mindedness and diversity across all dimensions of the University, generate knowledge that provides a context of learning from and contribution to India and the world, actively advance the social, economic, and ecological development of local, national, and international communities, educate young people of India and the world to become contextually-literate global citizens, and catalyze students to mature into critical thinkers who are analytically equipped, practically oriented, and ethically driven.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the interdisciplinary approach of Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University recognizes that social challenges and job opportunities are occurring at the intersection of various axes of influence, defined by disciplines (data, materials, biology, and behavior), nature (air, water, forests, and land), sectors of impact (health, transport, energy, and education), and society (individual and community). The university strives to guide students on how to learn through interdisciplinary academics and real-life experiences that traverse these intersections. Research programs at the University also embody this integrative philosophy",
  },
  {
    question: "What kind of graduates does Ahmedabad University produce ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University produces graduates with the capabilities, attitude, and values to excel in whatever field they choose to pursue around the world. These graduates are leaders of outstanding character who contribute significantly to their fields of study and practice, are contextually-literate global citizens, and are critical thinkers who are analytically equipped, practically oriented, and ethically driven."
  },
  {
    question: "How does Ahmedabad University contribute to society ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University actively advances the social, economic, and ecological development of local, national, and international communities by promoting independent-mindedness and diversity across all dimensions of the University, generating knowledge that provides a context of learning from and contribution to India and the world, and educating young people of India and the world to become contextually-literate global citizens."
  },
  {
    question: "Who established Ahmedabad Education Society ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad Education Society (AES) was established at the behest of Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel, the first Home Minister of India, by illustrious leaders such as Kasturbhai Lalbhai, Ganesh MavalanĨar, and Amrutlal Hargovandas."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the vision of Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The vision of Ahmedabad University is to advance education in the state of Gujarat, throughout India and the world, through open and unbounded thought leading humanity to prosperity."
  },
  {
    question: "What are some national institutions founded by AES and its leaders ?",
    answer: "AES and its leaders have played significant roles in the founding of national institutions such as the Indian Institute of Management Ahmedabad, the National Institute of Design, Physical Research Laboratory, and the Centre for Environmental Planning and Technology."
  },
  {
    question: "What are some institutions supported by Ahmedabad Education Society ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad Education Society is responsible for supporting reputed institutions such as MG Science Institute, LD Arts College, HL College of Commerce, LM College of Pharmacy, AG Teacher’s College and the LD Institute of Indology, amongst others."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the inspiration behind Ahmedabad University's logo ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University's logo is inspired by the rich heritage of the city of Ahmedabad, and features a stylised representation of an integral icon of the city - the stepwell, in the form of a minimalistic yet powerful graphic illustration."
  },
  {
    question: "What does the stepwell in Ahmedabad University's logo represent ?",
    answer: "The stepwell in Ahmedabad University's logo represents the University's focus on the enquiry for deep understanding. The channels and doors represent the openness ingrained in the holistic philosophy of education that Ahmedabad University embodies."
  },
  {
    question: "What programmes are offered at the Amrut Mody School of Management ?",
    answer: "The Amrut Mody School of Management offers undergraduate, graduate, and doctoral programmes in management, as well as short-term certificate courses for working professionals."
  },

  {
    question: "How does the School of Arts and Sciences at Ahmedabad University approach teaching ?",
    answer: "The School of Arts and Sciences at Ahmedabad University emphasises interdisciplinary, research-based teaching aimed at fostering a spirit of innovation and discovery. Students are provided with a rigorous foundation in the Major of their choice and have the opportunity to take courses spanning multiple divisions."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the focus of the School of Engineering and Applied Science at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The School of Engineering and Applied Science at Ahmedabad University emphasises project-based learning and a student-centric pedagogy aimed at creating an aptitude for design, innovation, and finding solutions for complex problems. The curriculum is contemporary and industry-oriented and offers specialisations ranging from Chemical Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, and Computer Science and Engineering to Applied Physics, Applied Chemistry, and Data Science and Analytics."
  },
  {
    question: "Are there any short-term certificate courses available at the School of Engineering and Applied Science ?",
    answer: "There is no mention of short-term certificate courses at the School of Engineering and Applied Science in the information provided."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the divisions of the School of Arts and Sciences ?",
    answer: "The School of Arts and Sciences at Ahmedabad University comprises five divisions: Biological and Life Sciences, Humanities and Languages, Mathematical and Physical Sciences, Performing and Visual Arts, and Social Sciences"
  },
  {
    question: "What is Ahmedabad Design Lab ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad Design Lab is a research, practice, and teaching space for understanding challenges facing our society and finding innovative solutions for the same. The Lab is premised on using design as the glue for bringing systems of Ĩnowledge from multiple disciplines for problem-solving."
  },
  {
    question: "What does the Centre for Heritage Management offer ?",
    answer: "The Centre for Heritage Management offers specialised education in heritage studies and professional management of diverse heritage resources, including monuments, crafts, museums, natural resources, tourism, urban development, as well as intangible heritage such as languages, music, customs and the performing arts.",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Centre for Learning Futures ?",
    answer: "The Centre for Learning Futures offers courses in communication and workshops in study skills intended to help you present ideas, comprehend better, and write effectively. The Centre has been set up to research innovation in teaching and learning, with a focus on the application of knowledge to the real world."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the ENABLE framework ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University has evolved a unique framework called 'Engagement and Application Based Learning and Education' or ENABLE in partnership with the Olin College of Engineering, Massachusetts, to facilitate learning by devising solutions to real-world problems."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Centre for Inter-Asian Research (CIAR) ?",
    answer: "The Centre for Inter-Asian Research (CIAR) aims to bring together scholars and practitioners to worĨ towards reimagining cultural, political, and economic structures across the continent. CIAR plans to focus on collaborative research projects across India and Asia, as well as interdisciplinary research and teaching across the Schools at Ahmedabad University."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the goals of CIAR ?",
    answer: "CIAR aims to put forward supple and innovative ideas about 'region' and 'neighbourhood', promote interdisciplinary worĨ that will foreground new axes of connection, past and present, set up flexible platforms and partnerships between scholars and practitioners in the Inter-Asia region, and build a Ĩnowledge base in India to understand and advance our relationship with other Asian societies."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Global Centre for Environment and Energy ?",
    answer: "The Global Centre for Environment and Energy addresses research needs at the interfaces of three vital global challenges - the environment, energy, and sustainability. The Centre aims to be a world leader in research and education to address global challenges through the interlinĨing of policy, entrepreneurship, science, and technology"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the International Centre for Space and Cosmology ?",
    answer: "The International Centre for Space and Cosmology is a research center focused on the areas of Space, Astrophysics, and Cosmology. It aims to drive cutting-edge research, train the next generation of researchers, and advance public understanding of this domain of Physics."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the goal of the International Centre for Space and Cosmology ?",
    answer: "The goal of the International Centre for Space and Cosmology is to conduct cutting-edge research in the areas of Space, Astrophysics, and Cosmology, train the next generation of researchers, and advance public understanding of this domain of Physics."
  },
  {
    question: "How does the International Centre for Space and Cosmology encourage young students ?",
    answer: "The International Centre for Space and Cosmology reaches out to young students to encourage them to consider a research career in Space and Cosmology and provides them with information regarding opportunities in these areas."
  },
  {
    question: "What is VentureStudio ?",
    answer: "VentureStudio is a startup incubation center at Ahmedabad University that offers a powerful environment for startups to build, launch and scale."
  },
  {
    question: "What kind of ecosystem does VentureStudio have ?",
    answer: "VentureStudio has a vibrant ecosystem that includes an experienced incubation team, a large network of industry and functional experts, angel and VC investors, and a community of like-minded startup founders."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the VentureStudio Fellowship Programme for Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The VentureStudio Fellowship Programme for Ahmedabad University is a 16-week intensive, hands-on, experiential, project-based, and multidisciplinary program designed to give students a real-life experience of starting an innovative business."
  },
  {
    question: "What topics will students dive into during the VentureStudio Fellowship Programme ?",
    answer: "During the VentureStudio Fellowship Programme, students will deep dive into many topics such as idea generation, business model canvas, marketing, finances, product-market fit, among several others."
  },
  {
    question: "What opportunities will students get during the VentureStudio Fellowship Programme ?",
    answer: "Apart from workshops conducted by subject area experts, students will also get an opportunity to interact closely with successful entrepreneurs, investors, and mentors during the VentureStudio Fellowship Programme."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the approach to teaching at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "At Ahmedabad University, the emphasis is on teaching students to think for themselves and link theoretical schemes to real-world contexts. The faculty have tailored a series of innovative courses that include studying the history of science through graphic novels, learning physics through constructing musical instruments, and being introduced to forensic biology by solving simulated crime scenes."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the role of interdisciplinarity at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Interdisciplinarity is a core value and guiding principle at Ahmedabad University. The university aims to create a unique system where students can actively shape their intellectual and educational trajectories by making use of the full range of the university's offerings. The belief is that students will thrive in an atmosphere where they are exposed to diverse perspectives and receive a comprehensive, well-rounded education."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the importance of positive and respectful interactions at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Positive and respectful interactions with a diverse group of peers can enhance one's understanding of self and others, the ability to work in teams, and inculcate open-mindedness crucial for developing innovative ideas. The university is committed to fostering a welcoming and respectful environment in which people from diverse backgrounds can reach their full potential."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the mission of Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The mission of Ahmedabad University is to provide a liberal education that prepares students to think deeply and creatively across multiple disciplines. The university aims to foster a sense of curiosity, an open mind, and a commitment to lifelong learning."
  },
  {
    question: "How does Ahmedabad University encourage students to shape their intellectual and educational trajectories ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University encourages students to shape their intellectual and educational trajectories by offering a wide range of courses and programs that allow students to explore their interests and passions. The university also emphasizes interdisciplinarity and encourages students to take courses outside of their major."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the philosophy behind Ahmedabad University's approach to education ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University's philosophy is to provide a liberal education that encourages students to think deeply and creatively, to question assumptions, and to be intellectually curious. The university believes in offering a well-rounded education that prepares students for lifelong learning and success in a rapidly changing world"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Foundation Programme at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The Foundation Programme is a one-of-its-kind programme in the world that exposes undergraduate students to societal issues through experiential learning. Students learn that collaboration between different disciplines is essential to solve problems facing humanity."
  },
  {
    question: "What are General Education Requirements at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "General Education Requirements are courses outside a student's Major that they are required to take. These courses allow students to pursue interests outside their Major and introduce them to new areas they may be interested in."
  },
  {
    question: "Can students pursue a Minor in a different area along with their Major at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Yes, students can pursue a Minor in a different area along with their Major at Ahmedabad University. This flexibility allows students to tailor their Programme the way they want it."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the opportunities for doctoral and master's students at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "At Ahmedabad University, doctoral and master's students have various opportunities to take courses in diverse areas to broaden their outlook and improve their skills. They can interact with renowned experts from other disciplines to build professional contacts and participate in different sports and other extracurricular activities depending on their interests."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the approach to learning at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The approach to learning at Ahmedabad University is hands-on. Students have the opportunity to pursue an Undergraduate Thesis or a Capstone Project in their final year of the Programme to apply what they have learnt at the University for answering a research question or solving a real-life problem."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the role of an undergraduate education at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The role of an undergraduate education at Ahmedabad University is to create well-rounded thinking citizens who will make meaningful contributions to society. The curriculum is designed to achieve this goal with a unique combination of breadth and depth that makes it challenging and engaging"
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the Dean of the Graduate School and Research at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The Dean of the Graduate School and Research at Ahmedabad University is Deepak Kunzru."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the role of the Dean of the Graduate School and Research at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The role of the Dean of the Graduate School and Research at Ahmedabad University is to oversee and manage the graduate programs, research activities, and related operations of the university."
  },
  {
    question: "What kind of opportunities will graduate students have at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Graduate students at Ahmedabad University will have opportunities to take courses in diverse areas, interact with experts from other disciplines, participate in extracurricular activities, and engage in research that addresses problems of societal relevance."
  },
  {
    question: "What kind of research is conducted by faculty at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Faculty at Ahmedabad University conduct both fundamental and applied research in diverse areas, with many of the research themes focused on solving problems of societal relevance."
  },
  {
    question: "How does Ahmedabad University provide a holistic education to graduate students ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University provides a holistic education to graduate students by encouraging them to think and tinker, rather than just memorize and reproduce, and by offering opportunities for academic, professional, and personal development"
  },
  {
    question: "How many semesters are there in the academic year 2022-2023 ?",
    answer: "There are two semesters in the academic year 2022-2023: Monsoon (August – December) and Winter (January – May)."
  },
  {
    question: "When does the Monsoon Semester for returning and incoming graduate students begin in the academic year 2022-2023 ?",
    answer: "The Monsoon Semester for returning and incoming graduate students begins on August 1, 2022."
  },
  {
    question: "When does the Winter Semester for returning and incoming graduate students begin in the academic year 2022-2023 ?",
    answer: "The Winter Semester for returning and incoming graduate students begins on January 9, 2023."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Summer Term in the academic year 2022-2023 ?",
    answer: "The Summer Term in the academic year 2022-2023 is from May 15, 2023 to July 28, 2023."
  },
  {
    question: "When is the Diwali Break in the academic year 2022-2023 ?",
    answer: "The Diwali Break in the academic year 2022-2023 is from October 15-16, 2022"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the academic calendar for the academic year 2022-2023 ?",
    answer: "The academic calendar for the academic year 2022-2023 runs on a semester system with two semesters - Monsoon (August - December) and Winter (January - May) and a Summer Term (May - June)."
  },
  {
    question: "When does the Monsoon Semester for returning students and incoming students of graduate programs start ?",
    answer: "The Monsoon Semester for returning students and incoming students of graduate programs starts on August 1, 2022."
  },
  {
    question: "When does the Monsoon Semester for incoming students of undergraduate and integrated masters programmes (except BTech) start ?",
    answer: "The Monsoon Semester for incoming students of undergraduate and integrated masters programmes (except BTech) starts on August 25, 2022."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the important dates for the Monsoon Semester for incoming students of undergraduate and integrated masters programmes (except BTech) ?",
    answer: `The important dates for the Monsoon Semester for incoming students of undergraduate and integrated masters programmes (except BTech) are as follows: \n
              Orientation: August 25-28, 2022 \n
              First Day of Classes: August 29, 2022\n
              Foundation Programme Begins: August 29, 2022\n
              Foundation Programme Ends: September 5, 2022\n
              Bi-Semester Courses Begin: October 28, 2022\n
              Mid Semester Examination Period: October 15-16, 2022\n
              Diwali Break: October 22-26, 2022\n
              Reflection and Review: November 14-18, 2022.`
  },
  {
    question: "When is the Quiet Reading Period for the Monsoon Semester ?",
    answer: "The Quiet Reading Period for the Monsoon Semester is from November 21-25, 2022."
  },
  {
    question: "When are the Mid Bi-Semester/End Semester Examinations for the Monsoon Semester ?",
    answer: "The Mid Bi-Semester/End Semester Examinations for the Monsoon Semester are from December 17-21, 2022."
  },
  {
    question: "When is the End Semester Examination Period for the Monsoon Semester ?",
    answer: "The End Semester Examination Period for the Monsoon Semester is from November 26-December 4, 2022."
  },
  {
    question: "When is the Semester Break for the Monsoon Semester ?",
    answer: "The Semester Break for the Monsoon Semester is from December 5, 2022, to January 8, 2023."
  },
  {
    question: "When is the Independent Study Period for the Monsoon Semester ?",
    answer: "The Independent Study Period for the Monsoon Semester is from December 5-23, 2022."
  },
  {
    question: "When does the Winter Semester for returning students and incoming students of graduate programs start ?",
    answer: "The Winter Semester for returning students and incoming students of graduate programs starts on January 9, 2023."
  },
  {
    question: "When does the Winter Semester for incoming students of undergraduate and integrated masters programmes (except BTech) start ?",
    answer: "The Winter Semester for incoming students of undergraduate and integrated masters programmes (except BTech) starts on January 9, 2023."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the important dates for the Winter Semester for incoming students of undergraduate and integrated masters programmes (except BTech) ?",
    answer: `The important dates for the Winter Semester for incoming students of undergraduate and integrated masters programmes (except BTech) are as follows:\n
              Quiet Reading Period for Bi-Semester Courses: February 18-21, 2023\n
              Mid Semester Examination Period: February 18-24, 2023\n
              Mid Semester/End Bi-Semester Examination: February 22-24, 2023\n
              Foundation Programme Begins: March 6, 2023; March 13, 2023`
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Examination Schedule at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The mid-term and end-term examinations of both semesters are scheduled during the stipulated time period mentioned in the academic calendar, and the exact schedules will be announced on the Ahmedabad University Resource Information System (AURIS)."
  },
  {
    question: "How can I keep track of other course specific evaluation dates ?",
    answer: "Other course specific evaluations such as quiz, project submission, viva voce, etc. are conducted throughout the semester, and their dates will be announced in the class. You are requested to keep track of these components through the course outline and course instructor's communication."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the goal of the Undergraduate Programme at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The Undergraduate Programme at Ahmedabad University is aimed at providing broad and deep education that will equip you to navigate the world in which you live and become an agent of change in the betterment of your own life and that of society. It provides immense flexibility to help each student discover their own passion and areas of engagement while developing capabilities to synthesize ideas and information and express themselves cogently."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the ethos that the University environment reflects ?",
    answer: "The University environment reflects empathy for others who are less endowed and a sense of duty towards contributing to society, whether through your own discipline or engagement with social organizations. Respect for and protection of other's ideas and beliefs, and their right to express them even when they are different from ours, should be the foremost object of the undergraduate experience."
  },
  {
    question: "What is an Honours degree at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "An Honours degree at Ahmedabad University, rooted in liberal education, calls for deep inquiry and perspective building that are highly valued by industry and society. It provides a transformational learning experience and requires academic rigor, including a comprehensive Foundation Programme and an Undergraduate Thesis or a Capstone Project. It takes most students four years to complete and requires completion of 120 credits or more (depending on the programme)"
  },
  {
    question: "What types of undergraduate programs are offered at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University offers Bachelor of Arts, Bachelor of Business Administration, Bachelor of Commerce, Bachelor of Science, Bachelor of Technology, Integrated Master of Business Administration, and Integrated Master of Science in Life Sciences."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the process for selecting a major at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Students can choose a major during their first year at the university and design their interdisciplinary major and accompanying program of study at the end of the second semester. Alternatively, a student can apply to transfer to an interdisciplinary major at any time. However, such a student may have to take an additional set of courses which may increase the duration to complete the program. Generally, very few proposals for interdisciplinary majors are accepted each year, so a student should have a traditional major in mind as an alternative."
  },
  {
    question: "What is a minor at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "A minor is an alternative area of specialization that is outside of one's major discipline. A minor can be taken in the same school or outside the school but cannot be in the same or closely related discipline as one's major. The purpose of the minor is to facilitate the building of alternative areas of expertise."
  },
  {
    question: "Is declaring a minor at Ahmedabad University mandatory ?",
    answer: "No, declaring a minor is optional although the university encourages students to declare a minor."
  },
  {
    question: "Can a student create a customized major at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Yes, the university provides flexibility for creating a customized major to meet the academic requirements of a very well-prepared student. Such a student may decide to undertake an interdisciplinary major or a self-designed major."
  },
  {
    question: "What are integrated programs at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Ahmedabad University offers two integrated programs. Students in integrated programs will be awarded two degrees at the bachelor's and master's levels in the same discipline. There will be an option to exit the integrated programs after four years with a bachelor's (honors) degree upon successful completion of the requirements for the bachelor's (honors) degree."
  },
  {
    question: "Is there any prerequisite for a major or minor at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Yes, there may be prerequisites specified for a major or minor in terms of preparation and academic achievement."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of an internship in the undergraduate program at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The purpose of an internship is to help guide a student's interest and decision making towards a major."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the requirements for completing an undergraduate programme that is not a Bachelor of Technology programme in Engineering ?",
    answer: "You will need to complete either an Undergraduate Thesis or a Capstone Project."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the credit requirement for the Undergraduate Programme in Business Administration and Commerce ?",
    answer: "The programme requires 125 credits."
  },
  {
    question: "How is the Undergraduate Programme in Business Administration and Commerce structured ?",
    answer: "The programme consists of a Foundation Programme (12 credits), General Education Requirements (30 credits), Major Requirements (65 credits), Free Electives and Minor (18 credits), and Volunteerism (required)."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the credit range for the Undergraduate Programmes in Arts and Sciences ?",
    answer: "The credit range is 120 to 123."
  },
  {
    question: "How are the Undergraduate Programmes in Arts and Sciences structured ?",
    answer: "Both programmes consist of a Foundation Programme (12 credits), General Education Requirements (30 credits), Major Requirements, Free Electives and Minor (18 credits), and Volunteerism (required)."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the Major Requirements for the BA/BS Physics and BS Computer Science programmes ?",
    answer: "The Major Requirements are 60 credits for both programmes."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the total credit requirement for the Integrated Master in Business Administration programme ?",
    answer: "The programme requires a total of 165 credits."
  },
  {
    question: "How is the Integrated Master in Business Administration programme structured ?",
    answer: "The programme consists of a Foundation Programme (12 credits), General Education Requirements (30 credits), Major Requirements (105 credits), Free Electives and Minor (18 credits), and Volunteerism (required)."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the credit requirement for the Integrated Master of Science in Life Sciences programme ?",
    answer: "The programme requires a total of 180 credits."
  },
  {
    question: "How is the Integrated Master of Science in Life Sciences programme structured ?",
    answer: "The programme consists of a Foundation Programme (12 credits), General Education Requirements (30 credits), Major Requirements (120 credits), Free Electives and Minor (18 credits), and Volunteerism (required)."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the credit requirement for the Undergraduate Programmes in Technology ?",
    answer: "The programme requires a total of 146 credits."
  },
  {
    question: "How is the Undergraduate Programmes in Technology structured ?",
    answer: "The programme consists of a Foundation Programme (12 credits), General Education Requirements (30 credits), Major Requirements (86 credits), Free Electives and Minor (18 credits), and Volunteerism (required)."
  },
  {
    question: "What categories of courses will students take within each programme ?",
    answer: "Students will take courses within the categories of Foundation Programme, General Education Requirements, Major Requirements, and Free Electives and Minor."
  },
  {
    question: "How many credits are required for the Foundation Programme ?",
    answer: "The Foundation Programme requires 12 credits."
  },
  {
    question: "How many credits are required for the General Education Requirements ?",
    answer: "The General Education Requirements require 30 credits."
  },
  {
    question: "How many credits are required for the Major Requirements ?",
    answer: "The Major Requirements credit requirement varies depending on the programme."
  },
  {
    question: "How many credits are required for the Free Electives and Minor ?",
    answer: "The Free Electives and Minor require 18 credits."
  },
  {
    question: "Is Volunteerism required for all programmes ?",
    answer: "Yes, Volunteerism is required for all programmes."
  },
  {
    question: "How many credits is one course worth ?",
    answer: "Most courses at the University are worth 3 credits."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the weekly time commitment for a course worth one credit ?",
    answer: "One credit roughly translates to 1 hour of instruction and 2 hours of study outside the classroom in a week"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Foundation Programme in the Undergraduate Curriculum at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The Foundation Programme is a common core program that all students go through in their first year. It builds the foundations of interdisciplinary enquiry at Ahmedabad University and enables students to engage with issues of society through project-based learning."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the six domains of engagement in the Foundation Programme at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The six domains of engagement in the Foundation Programme at Ahmedabad University are: 1. Data Science, 2. Communication, 3. Behaviour, 4. Constitution and Civilisation, 5. Biology and Life, and 6. Materials."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the four thematic studios in the Foundation Programme at Ahmedabad University in 2022 ?",
    answer: "The four thematic studios in the Foundation Programme at Ahmedabad University in 2022 are: 1. Democracy and Justice, 2. Environment and Climate Change, 3. Neighbourhoods, and 4. Water."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the goal of the thematic studios in the Foundation Programme at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The goal of the thematic studios in the Foundation Programme at Ahmedabad University is to engage students' imagination with contemporary problems encountered by society. Each theme is explored through a set of domains, creating interdisciplinary learning."
  },
  {
    question: "How are the foundational elements of the domains delivered in the Foundation Programme at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The foundational elements of the domains are delivered via four thematic studios that develop a holistic and hands-on approach to thinking, enquiry, and action. Students learn to understand multiple issues that define a problem, learn the art and science of synthesis, and design solutions to challenges."
  },
  {
    question: "How many credits does the Foundation Programme contribute to the total number of credits earned by students at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The Foundation Programme contributes 12 credits to the total number of credits earned by students at Ahmedabad University."
  },
  {
    question: "Does the Foundation Programme studio on Environment and Climate Change satisfy any requirement for a course on Environment at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Yes, the Foundation Programme studio on Environment and Climate Change satisfies any requirement for a course on Environment at Ahmedabad University."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Foundation Programme, and how does it prepare students for interdisciplinary learning ?",
    answer: "The Foundation Programme is a common core that all undergraduate students go through in their first year at Ahmedabad University. It is built around six domains of engagement, including data science, communication, behaviour, constitution and civilisation, biology and life, and materials. The programme is delivered through four thematic studios that develop a hands-on approach to thinking, enquiry, and action. Through the programme, students learn to identify issues of importance, study them, obtain information and data needed to analyse the issues, carry out the analysis, and offer solutions."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the General Education Requirements at Ahmedabad University, and what purpose do they serve ?",
    answer: "The General Education Requirements at Ahmedabad University aim to build a liberal arts influence in education and thinking and allow students to explore their interests outside their Major. These requirements comprise coursework in humanities and languages, social sciences, mathematical and physical sciences, biological and life sciences, and performing and visual arts. Additionally, one to three communications courses will also be included. At least three credits of coursework are required from each area, and the remaining 15 credits can be from any discipline at the University, except the Major discipline."
  },
  {
    question: "What is a Major, and what are the components of Major Requirements at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "A Major is the area of specialization within a degree, and the student chooses a Major at the time of entering the University. At Ahmedabad University, Major Requirements may have several components, including the School Core, Programme Core, Major Core, Major Electives, Engineering Foundation, Internships, and Undergraduate Thesis or Capstone Project or Bachelor of Technology Project with a writing component. The number of credits required for a Major may vary depending on the School's requirements, and students may have the flexibility to change their Major as per the prescribed policy."
  },
  {
    question: "What are Free Electives ?",
    answer: "Free Electives are courses that students can take from any discipline in the university to pursue a particular area in more depth, develop alternative areas of expertise, or learn more about many other areas of interest."
  },
  {
    question: "What is a Minor ?",
    answer: "A Minor is an opportunity for students to pursue alternative areas of interest in addition to a Major by taking a limited number of prescribed courses in a given area. At least 18 credits of coursework, as specified by the School, are required to complete a Minor, and the Free Electives can be applied towards a Minor."
  },
  {
    question: "Can a student take a Minor from any School of the University ?",
    answer: "Yes, students can take a Minor in any area from any School of the University, subject to satisfying any prerequisites for courses in the Minor."
  },
  {
    question: "Can a student take courses from other Schools of the University ?",
    answer: "Yes, students can take courses from other Schools of the University, subject to meeting the pre-requisites."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of the social service requirement ?",
    answer: "The purpose of the social service requirement is to build a value for action in all students' lives, to learn to give their efforts in service of others, and to build empathy in oneself."
  },
  {
    question: "Can a student change their Major ?",
    answer: "Yes, students can change their Majors, including moving to a Major hosted by a different School, subject to eligibility requirements and the approval of the Dean of the School hosting the new Major."
  },
  {
    question: "Can a student enter the University with an Undeclared Major ?",
    answer: "Yes, students can enter the University with an Undeclared Major and take courses to determine their passion and capabilities before selecting a Major, subject to eligibility requirements and the approval of the Dean of the School hosting the Major."
  },
  {
    question: "What majors are offered by the university ?",
    answer: "The university offers majors such as Accounting, Finance, Business Analytics, Marketing, Computer Science, Life Sciences, and more."
  },
  {
    question: "What is an Integrated Master's program ?",
    answer: "An Integrated Master's program is a five-year program that leads to both a Bachelor's and a Master's degree. It is expected that it would take five years to complete the program."
  },
  {
    question: "Can you exit an Integrated Master's program after four years ?",
    answer: "Yes, you can exit the Integrated program after four years with a Bachelor's (Honours) degree after having completed all the requirements of the program."
  },
  {
    question: "What graduate programs are offered by the university ?",
    answer: "The university offers several graduate programs such as Master of Arts in Economics, Master of Business Administration, Master of Technology in Chemical Engineering, Master of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering, and more."
  },
  {
    question: "What short-term diploma and certificate programs are offered by the university ?",
    answer: "The university offers short-term diploma and certificate programs such as Business Analytics, Financial Analysis, Strategic Digital Marketing, and Critical Thinking and the Liberal Arts."
  },
  {
    question: "What doctoral programs are offered by the university ?",
    answer: "The university offers a Doctoral program in Management and Engineering and an Interdisciplinary PhD in Humanities and Social Sciences. The requirements vary for the different doctoral programs which are offered by the respective schools and are overseen by the Graduate School."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the entry requirements for the Integrated Master's program ?",
    answer: "To enter the Integrated Master's program, you should have completed the requirements of Class XII."
  },
  {
    question: "What majors are available for Master's degree programs at the university ?",
    answer: "The university offers several Master's degree programs, including Master of Arts in Economics, Master of Business Administration, Master of Technology in Chemical Engineering, Master of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering, Master of Technology in Mechanical Engineering, Master of Management Studies in Heritage Management, Integrated Master in Business Administration, and Integrated Master of Science in Life Sciences."
  },
  {
    question: "Is there an option to earn both a Bachelor's and Master's degree with a single program ?",
    answer: "Yes, the Integrated Master's programs offered by the university lead to both a Bachelor's and Master's degree, awarded at the end of the program."
  },
  {
    question: "How long does it typically take to complete an Integrated Master's program ?",
    answer: "It is expected to take five years to complete an Integrated Master's program"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the role of the Deans of the Undergraduate College and the Schools ?",
    answer: "The Deans oversee the undergraduate learning experience, the Foundation Programme, and are responsible for the delivery of courses, Programmes and Majors, and all relevant academic and co-curricular experiences."
  },
  {
    question: "Who manages each Programme at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Each Programme is managed by a Programme Office which is headed by a Programme Chair who is a faculty member and a Programme Manager who is an administrative staff."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the role of the Programme Office ?",
    answer: "The Programme Office addresses all academic issues associated with a course or a programme, such as course registration, class scheduling, issuing ID cards, providing advice for the planning of course credits, resolving examination related queries, and processing student requests for programme change."
  },
  {
    question: "What is a Major Advisor ?",
    answer: "A Major Advisor is a faculty member who advises students about the academic requirements of each Major and helps them find appropriate courses and equivalents to successfully meet the requirements of the Major."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Circle of Care initiative ?",
    answer: "The Circle of Care initiative is designed for first-year students and each circle is led by a Faculty Advisor who helps address the queries of new students, assists students in transitioning from a school environment to a university, and acts as a guide who can advise in general or create linkages for the new student to access other resources."
  },
  {
    question: "What resources form the Student Advising System at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The multilevel resources that form the Student Advising System at Ahmedabad University include the Programme Office, Major Advisors, Faculty Advisors, and various other resources aimed at helping students navigate the educational experience as best as possible."
  },
  {
    question: "What kind of services are offered by the Programme Office ?",
    answer: "The Programme Office offers a variety of services to students including course registration and providing advice for the planning of course credits, class scheduling, issuing ID cards and duplicate ID cards, registration for anti-ragging compliance, room reservations for curricular, co-curricular and extracurricular activities, issuing various testimonials like no-objection certificates, bonafide, migration/transference certificates, transcripts, etc. and attestation of various documents, processing applications for government scholarships, educational verification for recruitment and further education, maintaining student records, processing applications for academic and unavoidable leaves, applying for grade drops and processing results, resolving examination related queries, serving as a single point of contact for student-related queries, communicating various informative notices to students, processing student requests for programme change, providing first aid, and processing admission cancellations."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the objective of a Course Fair at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "The objective of a Course Fair is to inform students about the courses being offered across Ahmedabad University, help them understand the objectives, content, and learning outcomes of various courses, and encourage them to take courses other than from their own Programme or School to make their learning more meaningful."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of Expression of Interest for Courses ?",
    answer: "The purpose of Expression of Interest for Courses is to offer an opportunity to students to express their interest in courses for all three semesters - Monsoon, Winter, Summer - and to assess demand for various courses across the University before the Pre-Registration period. Priority will be given in registration to those students who have responded in the Expression of Interest."
  },
  {
    question: "When does the Pre-Registration period start for the Monsoon Semester at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "Generally, the Pre-Registration period for the Monsoon Semester starts in the first week of May of each academic year."
  },
  {
    question: "What happens if a student does not pay the fees before the due date during the course registration period ?",
    answer: "If a student does not pay the fees before the due date mentioned by the University during the course registration period, the courses chosen during the pre-registration phase will be removed from the student's selection, and the student will need to re-register for the courses."
  },
  {
    question: "Can a student drop a course after the Add/Drop month is over at Ahmedabad University ?",
    answer: "No, a student cannot drop any course that he/she has registered for after the Add/Drop month is over. However, if a student wishes to do so due to exceptional circumstances, he/she may only do so with the approval of the Programme Chair, the Associate Dean, or the Dean of the School to which he/she belongs. The request may be approved or rejected based on the circumstances and the explanation offered by the student."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the first step in the Course Registration procedure ?",
    answer: "The first step in the Course Registration procedure is for students to log in to www.auris.ahduni.edu.in with the credentials provided."
  },
  {
    question: "What should students do if they have paid the fees but are unable to register for a course ?",
    answer: "If students have paid the fees but are unable to register for a course, they need to contact their Programme Office. The Programme Office will verify the payment status and facilitate the registration."
  },
  {
    question: "Where can students find available courses from all schools ?",
    answer: "Students can find available courses from all schools by clicking on the course registration tab and using the course search facility to search for courses by course codes, course names, professor’s name, keywords of the course description, etc."
  },
  {
    question: "How many courses can students choose beyond their maximum credit load as a preference ?",
    answer: "Students can choose three courses beyond their maximum credit load as a preference."
  },
  {
    question: "What should students do if a course has a pre-requisite ?",
    answer: "If a course has a pre-requisite, students must complete the pre-requisite course(s) first before they can register for the course."
  },
  {
    question: "What should students do if a course has a co-requisite ?",
    answer: "If a course has a co-requisite, students must register for the co-requisite course first before they can register for the course."
  },
  {
    question: "What is an anti-requisite ?",
    answer: "If a course has an anti-requisite, it means that students cannot register for the course if they have already completed the listed anti-requisite as the courses contain substantially equivalent content."
  },
  {
    question: "What is auditing ?",
    answer: "Auditing is an option where students perform limited work based on their agreement with the Professor. Students do not receive a letter grade but get a Satisfactory/ Unsatisfactory completion status, and this does not count in the Grade Point Average or Graduation."
  },
  {
    question: "How to register for courses ?",
    answer: `To register for courses at Ahmedabad University, you can follow these steps:\
              Course Fairs: \n
                Contact: Programme Chairs or Deans of Schools\n
                Period: April 16-26 for Monsoon and Summer, October 16-26 for Winter\n\n
              Expression of Interest: \n
                Contact: Programme Chairs or Deans of Schools\n
                Period: April 16-26 for Monsoon and Summer, October 16-26 for Winter \n\n
              Pre-Registration:\n
                Period: First week of May for Monsoon Semester, first week of November for Winter Semester Registration:\n
                Contact: University Period: July for Monsoon Semester, December for Winter Semester, last week of May for Summer Semester\n\n 
              Add/Drop:\n
              Contact: Programme Chair, Associate Dean, or Dean of the School\n
              Period: First month of classes Note: Students must pay all fees before final registration starts or by the due date mentioned by the University.\n\n
            Additionally, students who have applied for Financial Aid will be communicated the decision regarding the aid separately, before the course registration starts.`
  },
  {
    question: "Where is the Cafeteria",
    answer: `There are three cafeteria: \
              ●	Cafeteria at the University center having Truly Indian, Cafe Delice, Global Bistro and Greens and Grains as your choices
              ●	Project Otenga offering North Eastern Cuisine along with other varieties
              ●	Cafe Venture Studio `
  },
  {
    question: "How is Ahmedabad University's student life",
    answer: `●	Vibrant student community\
            ●	Strong support system\
            ●	Easily accessible resources\
            ●	Numerous extracurricular activities and events\
            ●	Opportunities to explore and immerse yourselves in the culture\
    `
  },
  {
    question: "How is Ahmedabad University's spirit",
    answer: `●	Self and society\
            ●	Help ourselves and others improve\
            ●	Don't give up and help others not to give up\
            ●	Celebrate when others win because it inspires us to do our best`
  },
  {
    question: "What are the four pillars of our education",
    answer: `●	Diversity\
             ●	Interdisciplinarity\
             ●	Experiential Learning\
             ●	Research Thinking`
  },
  {
    question: "What is AUSEAC",
    answer: `●	AUSEAC (part of the office of Dean of Students) oversees the functioning of all the university student clubs and coordinates various events.\
             ●	It sets criteria for and approves the establishment of new student cubs and organizes University level events.`
  },
  {
    question: "Who is a part of the AUSEAC committee",
    answer: "Jatin Christie, Shilpa Pandit, Zalak Shah, Jayendra Bhalodiya, Keita Omi, Nisha Nankani, Veena Shirsath, Nandini Rajesh, Mohnish Mirchandani, Hardi Talwani, Santvana Ganatra, Hetal Jhaveri, Ravi Miglani, Aditya Kanth and Aravind Panicker"
  },
  {
    question: "How many student clubs are there in Ahmedabad University",
    answer: `There are a total 19 student clubs. There are as follow:\
             Dance Club, Design Club, Entrepreneurs Club, Environment Club, Film Appreciation Club, Fine arts Club, Fitness Club, Food and Nutrition Club, Heritage Club, Literary Club, Management Club, Music Club, Photography Club, Programming Club, Quiz Club, Social Service Forum, Sports Club, Students Magazine Club and Theatre Club`
  },
  {
    question: "Associations of Ahmedabad University",
    answer: `●	Ahmedabad University Student’s Branch of IEEE which desires to give all students an equal opportunity to venture out into new possibilities and promote a project based environment. Website: www.ieee.ahduni.edu.in \
             ●	Robotics and Automation  Society Student Chapter fosters the development and facilitates the exchange of scientific and technological knowledge in Robotics and Automation among students and members. Website: www.ieee.ahduni.edu.in/ras\
             ●	Women in Engineering Affinity Group focus on enhancing the participation of women in society and bettering their skills needed for entrepreneurship.\
             ●	American Institute for Chemical Engineers (AIChE) Student Chapter promotes professional development through programmes through activities involving faculty and student members.`
  },
  {
    question: "Cultural Programmes of Ahmedabad University",
    answer: "The university has been the venue for the two week long renowned Indian Classical musical festival of Ahmedabad, “Saptak”. It also hosts music festivals, state and international level quiz competitions, project proposal programmes and social events."
  },
  {
    question: "Sports, Athletics and Wellness of Ahmedabad University",
    answer: "Students have access to outstanding sports facilities such as University grounds AES Sports Complex, a cricket ground, a basketball court, a volleyball court, table tennis court and more."
  },
  {
    question: "What is a circle of care",
    answer: " In order to assist fresh undergraduate students through the phase of transition from school to college, incoming class is distributed into groups of 12-14 to form a friends circle which is paired with Faculty advisor and a student Mitr (friend) who is a senior student.Circle of care also includes Programme chairs, the University Counsellor and the career development center to provide emotional support and additional academic and career guidance."
  },
  {
    question: "What are university wide extra curricular activities",
    answer: `Yamini is an annual all night Indian music concert in collaboration with the Society for the Promotion of Indian Classical Music and Culture Amongst Youth (SPIC MACAY) dedicated to the rich heritage of classical music and performing arts in India.\
             Anand Mela conducted by social service forum club for children from 5 to 15 years of age group from underserved and underprivileged communities to show that education can be fun.`
  },
  {
    question: "What are the services provided by the Career Development Centre",
    answer: "The University's Career Development Centre helps prepare students for careers after their university education. It provides career counseling in areas of interest, information on various industries, and guidance to those seeking graduate education. It also organizes psychometric tests and workshops that give students a better sense of their own strength, development areas and the kind of work that aligns to their innate abilities."
  },
  {
    question: "What are the services provided by the Centre for Learning Futures",
    answer: `●	Reading and Writing Centre- It offers courses that train students in evidence based reading and writing.\
             ●	Writer's Studio- It is an initiative to give detailed and personalized feedback on student's writing by trained professionals in journalism, communication and management.\
             ●	Ahmedabad Tutoring Programme- It is a peer tutoring programme to help students in clarifying doubts or to overcome academic difficulties.`
  },
  {
    question: "What are teaching and research assistantships",
    answer: "Teaching assistants support faculty with course management while research assistants support faculty on their research."
  },
  {
    question: "Do we have a campus shuttle",
    answer: "We have a campus shuttle bus service for students to travel between various campuses. Find the designated bus stops and timings to use it for moving about the university."
  },
  {
    question: "Do we have university bus service",
    answer: "We have a campus shuttle bus service for students to travel within the city and its suburbs as well as those coming from Gandhinagar. Find the designated bus stops and timings to use for moving about the city and more routes can be added as per the convenience of the students."
  },
  {
    question: "What wellness or counseling services are available in the university",
    answer: `●	Health services: Wellness center has free medical consultations available within the campus as well as regularly holds health related camps and campaigns.\
             ●	Personal Counseling:  Ahmedabad University encourages all to tend to your emotional needs which is provided through a wellness center who provides counselors who are available to all for walk-in consultations as well as sustained therapeutic engagement.`
  },
  {
    question: "What is Ahmedabad University’s policy for Sexual Harassment, Anti-Ragging and Grievance Redressal",
    answer: `
        ●	Prevention of Sexual Harassment: Ahmedabad University has a stringent policy against sexual harassment, which is widely condened as a form of human rights violation, an infringement on life and liberty and a grave form of gender based discrimination. Sexual harassment of any level is a punishable offense. As per Sexual Harassment of Women at Workplace (Prevention, Prohibition and Redressal) Act 2013, an internal committee has been constituted who can be contacted for any complaints.\
        ●	Anti- Ragging Policy: The University has strictly prohibited ragging and will take any required actions to prevent and deter the recurrence of such incidences. Any student found indulging and/or abetting any form of ragging shall face disciplinary action, including the possible debarring of such students from taking admissions in any institutions of higher learning in the country.For concerns or complaints regarding ragging, please email: dean.students@ahduni.edu.in\
        ●	Grievance Redressal: Students may express grievances by filling out the Grievance Redressal Form available on the website and submit it to the Director/ Dean of the concerned School/ Centre.\
        ●	Internal committee: Saptam Patel (Chairperson), Kalpana Pareek, Dharamashi Rabari, Saumil Shah, Aditi Singhal, Sonia Kumar, Malti Mehta (NGO Member), Simran Nasra, Parth Saxena and Srusthti Dave.`
  },
  {
    question: "What is a University's Disciplinary System",
    answer: `The student's Code of Conduct, available on AURIS, details the University's disciplinary system and we expect each one of you to follow it. All incoming students have to read and understand the Code of Conduct.\
             The Disciplinary Committee for Non -Academic Transgressions by students looks into any non-academic transgressions by students.`
  },
  {
    question: "Where to get Books and University Merchandise",
    answer: `Books: The books and the course packs will be provided to you by the Programme Office at the beginning of the semester.\
             University Merchandise:  University merchandise such as t-shirts, mugs, caps, water bottles etc are available at the bookstore in the University Center. The surplus generated from merchandise goes towards the student financial aid fund.`
  },
  {
    question: "What is necessary financial information for students",
    answer: `
  ●	Tuition Fees: \n
    Please consult AURIS and the Office of Admissions and Financial Aid for details about Tuition Fees and payment process. For fees related query you may contact: fees@ahduni.edu.in \n\n\n
  ●	Financial Aid: \n
    The University admits students on a need blind basis and firmly believes that lack of financial resources should not be a barrier to education. Partial and complete waiver of tuition fees is provided to students based on eligibility. Merit scholarships are offered in recognition of academic achievements of students.\n\n\n
  ●	Need Based Scholarship:\n
    The University admits students on a need blind basis and firmly believes that lack of financial resources should not be a barrier to education. Partial and complete waiver of tuition fees is provided to students based on eligibility.Students requiring financial aid should contact the Office of Admissions and Financial Aid after receiving the offer of admission. (student will have to maintain a minimum of CGPA 2.0 for maintaining the scholarship)\n\n\n
  ●	Merit Scholarships: \n
                Merit scholarships are offered in recognition of academic achievements of students.\n\n\n
  ●	Student Insurance:\n
    All students enrolled at Ahmedabad University get access to two types of insurance:\n
      ●	Group Health Insurance (GHI) that provides up to INR 1 lakh per student in case of hospitalization and covers pre-existing health conditions and daycare treatments. You must file claims within 20 days of being discharged.\n
      ●	Group Personal Accident (GPA) that provides up to INR 1 lakh in case of Accidental Death and any form of permanent disability. \n\n
  For more details email: insurance@ahduni.edu.in`
  },
  {
    question: "What are contacts for emergencies",
    answer: `- University Office (8am to 7pm):                                +91.079.61911000/200/201
     - Security Supervisor (24 hours):                                +91.94265 66502 
     - Security (AMSOM Undergraduate - East Campus): +91.079.61911782 
     - Security (AMSOM - Central Campus):                      +91.079.61911180 
     - Security (SEAS - Central Campus):                          +91.079.61911180 
     - Security (SAS BLS - South Campus):                       +91.079.61911277 
     - Doctor on-campus:                                                    +91.079.61911026/1099 
     - Anti-Ragging Helpline:                                               1800.180.5522 
     - Suicide Prevention Helpline:                                      1860.266.2345 
     - Women's Helpline:                                                     1091, 181 
     - Gujarat Police Helpline:                                             1995 
     - Ambulance:                                                                108 
     - Blood Bank:                                                                1910 
     - Indian Red Cross Society (Gujarat State Branch):     +91.079.27557055/56 
     - Memnagar Fire Station:                                              +91.079.27911331 
     - Animal Welfare (Jivdaya Charitable Trust):                +91.9924418184
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What are the campus contacts",
    answer: `1.Registrar: University Office No.2\n
    +91.079.61911200/1201\n
    bm.shah@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
 
 2.Director, Campus Operations: University Office No.3\n
    +91.079.61911200/1201\n
     director.campusoperations@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
 
 3.Student Insurance: University Office No.2\n
    +91.079.61911200/1201\n
     insurance@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
 
 4.Head, Operations: University Office No.2\n
    +91.079.61911200/1201 \n
    ridul.deka@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
 
 5. Director, Office of Housing and Residential Life: University Residences FLH 2, Gulbai Tekra,Navrangpura, Ahmedabad 380009 \n
      +91.9910073125\n
      director.studentresidences@ahduni.edu.in\n
 `
  },
  {
    question: "What are various university addresses",
    answer: `Facilities and Services\n\n
    1.Colonel Vinit Menon\
    Director, Campus Operations \
    +91.079.6191124\n\n
    
    2.Mr Vallabhan \
    Executive Security \
    +91.9426566502 \n\n
    
    3.Mr Abhinav Chaturvedi \
     Executive\
    (Travel Desk & Events)(Central and East Campuses) \
    +91.9638197907\n\n
    
    4.Central Facility Helpdesk\
    +91.79.61911001/1002\
    facilityhelpdesk@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
    
    5.SAS Building Office\
    +91.079.61911547\n\n
    
    6.Bio Nest\
    +91.079.61911580\n\n
    
    7.GICT Building Office\
       +91.079.61911183\n\n
    
    8.Biosciences Research Laboratory\
       +91.079.61911253\n\n\n
    
    Administrative Offices\n\n
    
    1. University Office\
    +91.079.61911000/1200/1201\
    info@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
    
    2.Office of Academic Registrar: North Campus\
    +91.079.61911000/1200/1201\
    academic.registrar@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
    
    3.Office of the undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aid: University Office No.5\
    +91.079.61911217/1219\
    +91.9979036969, +91.9979036868\
    ugadmissions@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
    
    4.Office of the Dean Students: 200,University Centre\
    +91.079.61911029/1038\
    wellness@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
    
    5.Career Development Centre: 401, University Centre\
    +91.079.61911078/1079\
    career.development@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
    
    6.Office of International Affairs: 206, University Centre\
    +91.079.61911033\
    international.aff\airs@ahduni.edu.in\n\n\n
    
    Programme Offices\n\n
    
    1. Biological and Life Sciences\
    SAS, South Campus\
    +91.079.61911253/1258\
    artsandsciences@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
    
    2.School of Engineering and Applied Sciences\
    Room No. 019, GICT Building, Central Campus\
    +91.079.61911111/1112\
    office_seas@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
    
    3.Amrut Mody School of Management\
    Heritage Building, Central Campus\
    +91.079.61911350\
    ug.programmeoffice@ahduni.edu.in\n\n
    
    4.School of Arts and Sciences\
    SAS Building, Central Campus\
    +91.079.61911502\
    artsandsciences@ahduni.edu.in
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What are university websites",
    answer: `www.ahduni.edu.in\
    www.ahduni.edu.in/amsom\
    www.ahduni.edu.in/sas\
    www.ahduni.edu.in/seas\
    www.ahduni.edu.in/chm\
    www.ahduni.edu.in/vs\
    www.ahduni.edu.in/centre-for-learning-futures\
    www.ahduni.edu.in/global-centre-for-environment-and-energy\
    www.ahduni.edu.in/icsc\
    www.ahduni.edu.in/ciar\
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What types of internships are to be done",
    answer: `- Summer Internship\
    - Integrated MBA Internship
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What are summer internships",
    answer: "The summer internship will offer you an experience of a professional environment and an opportunity to gather specific skills towards employment. It is very useful as it allows you to explore areas in which you would like to work after graduation or even search for your interests in Graduate programmes. It is a valuable way of connecting with the industry and often becomes a stepping stone for receiving a job offer. Most of our Programmes have a mandatory internship requirement."
  },
  {
    question: "What is an Integrated MBA Internship",
    answer: "The six-month internship for Integrated MBA students is a Students from carefully planned and monitored work experience with an International Im aim to gain additional knowledge It provides an opportunity to our management students to spend an entire semester in an organization. The internship provides exposure to the real business world which cannot be simulated in the classroom and, hence, the internships help create competent professionals for the industry. A student is expected to spend one semester (22 to 24 weeks) in an organization and carry out an independent business project under the guidance of mentors both from the University and the internship organization. Total Credits for Internship - 12 credits When Final Semester of the Programme."
  },
  {
    question: "What is International Immersion",
    answer: "In an attempt to provide better global business acumen in a more holistic global context, the Integrated MBA programme provides a platform where students study short- term courses at foreign universities universities to explore and understand the nuances of conducting business in that particular geographic domain. This immersion is a compulsory part of the Integrated MBA programme and is associated with 2 credits. Students are expected to contribute to all the international immersion expenses including academic fees, international flight, visa, insurance, lodging, boarding, excursion, etc. The University. will facilitate the process.Students from other programmes can also explore International Immersion that is offered to them."
  },
  {
    question: "What are transcripts",
    answer: "Students can view the record of their grades, which have already been announced by the course instructor and the programme office, on AURIS If you require a printed copy of your transcript (grade sheet), you should contact your respective programme office."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Independent Study Period",
    answer: "Students of Ahmedabad University have the option of Independent Study, also known as directed study, where they can undertake the study of a subject they are interested in beyond the curriculum with the help of a faculty for predetermined credits. An Independent Study enables a proactive student to pursue the study of a topic or interest that is not a part of the set academic curriculum, leading the way to gain specialized knowledge or gain specific research. experience Find a faculty member who will be willing to be your guide in the Independent Study project. You and the faculty member should agree on the scope, the deliverables and the evaluation criteria for the Independent Study for you to pursue it. You will have to register for Independent Study as a course"
  },
  {
    question: "What is Undergraduate thesis or Capstone project",
    answer: `
    Students, especially at the undergraduate level, have varying aspirations after the completion of their degree Most would like to look for a job after their undergraduate degree, many pursue a master's programme (sometimes in their own discipline or in a profession) and a few pursue graduate study leading to a doctoral degree Academic programmes also wish to emphasize on training that prepares you for a career, apart from one that defines the culmination of your learning in the programme Often a thesis or a capstone project is used to meet such diverse career requirements and preparation\n
    A Thesis is a scholarly document that examines a focused or a narrow issue or a problem and evaluates it analytically, critically, and in depth to often suggest a suitable direction for a solution It could also be an analysis of a situation or a perspective or a point of view that deepens our understanding of the area and the issues under study. A Thesis could be a critical analysis of a book(s), an idea(s), testing of a hypothesis with data that involves a review of related literature and development of an analytical solution, development of a theoretical model, an engagement with a scholarly debate in the discipline, etc. A Thesis should be done individually, and it prepares you as a student to undertake independent research and teaches you about methods of enquiry. It helps build deep knowledge in one narrow domain A Thesis is suitable for a student who wishes to pursue graduate studies leading to doctoral education and/ or perhaps build a research-oriented career\n
    A Capstone Project is o broad, multifaceted, application-oriented project where students get an opportunity to apply what they have learned to a practical situation or integrate real-world experiences and draw inferences, build a product or service, address important community issues or historical issues based on data and evidence, etc The Capstone Project involves structuring an unstructured problem, research, collection of data, development of options and their critical analysis, generation of recommendations and insights, and a convincing presentation (written, oral, and/ or using other media). The Capstone Project provides a significant value in training a student for professional life These projects are typically sponsored by an organization (whether governmental/ non governmental or non profit/ for profit) or in rare cases, motivated by a real problem or issue. A Capstone Project is a group project, preferably an interdisciplinary group across Majors, Programmes and Schools. It is also meant to train you as a young leader in problem solving and to work in teams.`
  },
  {
    question: "What is Course Catalog and Course Outline",
    answer: "A Course Catalog n a compilation of all courses offered in any semester which you will consult to identify courses that interest you and those you could finally opt for This is central to our Choice Based Credit System Courses are announced with details regarding the number of days, time of the week, and the Instructor who would be teaching it You can choose courses as per a schedule that you wish to have for the Semester While selecting, keep in mind that you must meet certain credit requirements each Semester to graduate in a stipulated time and that certain courses will have prerequisites As a result, you will have to bear in mind the sequence of courses to meet your requirements. Each Major provides a sample study plan to help you. design your own You do not have to follow the sample plan but must build one for yourself, keeping your needs and interests in mind. Details of each course are provided in a Course Outline which includes a description of the course, learning outcomes, a session plan, assessment component and pattern of grading, reference material, etc. You should carefully understand each course outline and refer to it regularly as the course progresses as it will carry many instructions for the Programme."
  },
  {
    question: "How does assessment and grading work",
    answer: "Components of assessment and the pattern of grading may vary between Courses These would be described in each Course Outline. The same Course may be offered with varying requirements in different semesters. Programmes may require different levels of achievements in the same Course depending on how salient that Course is for the Programme You are advised to refer to the programme requirements for further information. Passed/ Not Passed grades Certain Courses may be offered as Passed/ Not Passed For such Courses, credits will be earned, but letter grades will not be assigned. The transcript will show Passed/ Not Passed"
  },
  {
    question: "What do you mean by my GPA (Grade Point average)",
    answer: "A Grade Point Average or a GPA weighted average the grades obtained by you during a Semester, while a Cumulative Grade Point Average of a CGPA indicates the weighted average of the grades obtained by you in all the Courses that you have taken until any point of time."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Grading System",
    answer: `Ahmedabad University follows the GPA system on a scale of 4.00. The letter grade, grade points, and their respective qualitative meanings of given in the table below. For students admitted from 2019 onwards
    Format is: Letter Grade | Grade Point Qualitative | Meaning
               A | 4.0 | Excellent
               A- |  3.7 | Very Good
               B+ |  3.3 | Very Good
               B | 3.0 | Good
               B- | 2.7 | Good
               C+ | 2.3 | Fair
               C | 2.0 | Fair
               D | 1.7 | Sufficient
               NP | 0 | Not Passed
               P | 0 | Passed
               I | - | Incomplete
               W | - | Withdrawn from Course
               S | 0 | Satisfactory
               U | 0 | Unsatisfactory\n\n
    Lateral admissions will be treated at par with their peer group admitted in the previous years. While each Instructor may decide to give marks or grades for various components, they are finally converted into a course grade. Course grading could be absolute or relative as per the choice of the Instructor. This implies that the level of achievement required or marks required to receive a particular grade may vary by the Course.`
  },
  {
    question: "What are academic standards",
    answer: "Minimum passing grade in each Course D with grade point of 1.7 out of 4.00 At the same time, the overall posing requirement for the Undergraduate and Master's degree programmes is a CGPA of 2.00 out of 4.00 A minimum CGPA of 2.7 out of 4.00 is required for Doctoral programmes."
  },
  {
    question: "What does NP mean",
    answer: `An NP grade in a Course indicates that the student has not met the minimum passing requirement in that Course. This has several implications:\
    If an NP is given in a Counse required for a certain Programme, the student has to repeat the same Course or an equivalent Course and needs to pass that course in order to be eligible for graduation.\
    If an NP is given in an elective, the student can repeat the same Course or undertake any other Course he/she is eligible for and complete it successfully, to meet the total credit requirement for graduation.\
    An NP grade in a Course that is a prerequisite for an advanced level course may prevent the student from taking the advanced level course until the prerequisite one is cleared with a specified grade.`
  },
  {
    question: "What does an I grade mean",
    answer: `An I Grade indicates incomplete, which means that the student has not completed the coursework and/ or the evaluation for a specific Course for various reasons. I Grade will remain on the grade sheet until the student completes all the course requirements. A time frame may be specified to convert an I Grade to a Course Grade. If the student is unable to fulfill course requirements within the stipulated time, I Grade will get converted into NP/F Grade.\n
    An I Grade has the following implications:\n
    The student may not be allowed to register for an advanced level course, for which the Course in which he/she obtained an I Grade is a prerequisite\n
    The student may have to register for another Course, if the one in which he/she has been given an I Grade is an elective, in order to complete the degree requirements`
  },
  {
    question: "What are academic standards and integrity",
    answer: "Students are required to maintain the highest level of integrity and abstain from any kind of academic malpractice while studying at the University. You are required to understand the integrity standards of the University so that you are aware of what constitutes practice in education. This includes and not Limited to staying away from any act of copying during any mode of examination evaluation, act of copying homework or assignments plagiarism of any sort, and ensuring timely submission of all assignments, project work, etc Corrective and/ or punitive actions shall be taken in case any students found to be involved in any kind of academic malpractice. This could also lead to dismissal from the University."
  },
  {
    question: "What does transfer of credit mean",
    answer: "Coursework undertaken at a university institute other than Ahmedabad University may be considered towards the degree requirement at Ahmedabad. The credits earned by a student outside Ahmedabad University will be transferred on the basis of the academic rigor of the coursework done elsewhere. Not all coursework undertaken outside Ahmedabad may be eligible for consideration. Students are advised to seek assistance from the Programme Chars to understand whether the coursework done by them outside Ahmedabad will be considered for credit transfer or not, and the proportion of the credits that will be transferred. Credits and the Grades transferred from other universities/institutions will not be included in the calculation of the CGPA. However, such credits, if earned successfully, will be counted towards the total credit requirement for graduation."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Attendance Policy",
    answer: `Attendance: \n
      - Classes and academic activities will be scheduled from 8:00 am to 8:30 pm.\n
      - You should attend guest lectures and/ or events that may be organized on working days/ holidays. These are important opportunities to learn and grow.\n
      - You are expected to attend 100 percent of all classes you have enrolled for, irrespective of the minimum attendance requirements. If you do not fulfill minimum attendance requirements you will get a grade drop or may not be permitted to appear for the examination or both.\n\n
    
    Please note: A minimum attendance criterion applies to each Course separately. Please check with the concerned faculty and Course Outline for details.\n
    The academic programme at Ahmedabad University is based on rigorous academic engagement in the classroom. Hence, if classes are missed then learning gets compromised. It is not possible to capture each and every aspect of this learning through evaluations such as examinations. Therefore, if you miss a significant portion of classes then grades have to be dropped and adjusted downwards for the learning compromised on account of absence.\n    
    It is expected that you will aim to attend 100 percent of the sessions for every Course you have registered for in any Semester. It is understood that some exigencies may come up on account of which you may miss some classes. Factoring in such probable exigencies, there are no adverse consequences in a Course if the attendance falls up to 80 percent in it. However, if the attendance of the student in any course falls below 80 percent then the Grade in that course will drop. There is one Grade Drop for every shortfall of 15 percent below 80 percent attendance. However, if the attendance falls below 50 percent then the student will get an NP Grade and they will have to repeat the Course. This policy encourages the students to maintain higher attendance and ensures that no learning is missed.\n
    However, for a particular course, the Course Instructor may define a different attendance policy more stringent than this. The Attendance Policy of a particular course shall supersede the overall University Attendance Policy.\n
    The following is an indication of how the Grade Drop is applied:\n
    Format: Percentage of attendance | Final grade if a student has an 'A' before drop | Final grade if a student has an 'B' before drop\n\n
            80 or more | A | B\n
            65-79.99 | A- | C+\n
            50-64.99 | B+ | C\n
            Below 50 | NP | NP\n\n
    
    If a student's grade drops below 'D' due to Grade Drops then he or she will receive an 'NP' grade, even if the attendance is 50 per cent or above.    
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What is authorized absence",
    answer: `Students may participate in certain external events and academic and co-curricular engagements. At times these may coincide with the academic schedule at the University. These could be conferences where students are presenting papers, sports events or other competitions of high repute where our students are representing the University or other similar events.There is a provision to grant authorized absence to students for some sessions or for a half/ full day/ days depending on the nature of their engagement and their participation therein. You will have to apply in advance to your Programme Chair who will forward the application to the School Dean for approval. If Authorized Absence is approved, your Programme Chair will convey this to all other Programme Chairs and Programme Managers. You must inform all the concerned instructors whose sessions you are going to miss. You are responsible to make up for the missed learning in consultation with the Course Instructor. The compensatory effort to be put in by you will be as decided by the Instructor and approved by the corresponding Dean. The compensatory effort can be in the form of extra reading, a written review of the missed learning, extra assignments, an additional term paper, additional laboratory sessions, project work, following recorded lectures or lectures available online, etc. In the case of Authorized Absences, the grade drop will apply if your total number of Authorized and Additional Absences is more than 20% of the sessions, and you have had more than 2 Additional Absences. (The term Additional Absences above does not include Unavoidable Absences)\n\n  
    Note: This policy only changes the manner in which Grade Drop applies in case of Authorized Absence. A student is not marked present for sessions missed.`
  },
  {
    question: "What is unavoidable absence",
    answer: `In some cases, due to medical situations, family tragedies, etc. the absence of the student is unavoidable. In such cases, a student may be granted Unavoidable Absence. The student should apply to their Programme Chair for the same\n

    Just as in the case of Authorized Absence, Grade drops will apply in Unavoidable Absence if the student's total number of absences is more than 20 per cent and the student has had more than 2 Additional Absences. (The term Additional Absence refers to additional Unauthorized Absences)\n
    
    The student is responsible to make up for the missed learning in consultation with the course instructor as in the case of Authorized Absence.\n
    In case the number of Unavoidable Absences exceeds 20 percent of the total number of sessions, in select cases, the instructor may suggest that the student take an Incomplete Grade (1) for the course or Withdraws (W) from the course.\n
    
    In case of genuine medical situations, where the student has taken long leave, he/she will be granted Unavoidable Absence only after the University Doctor certifies that the student is fit to attend the University, and that she is convinced of the genuineness of the illness. The certificate of the University Doctor will be submitted to the Programme Office by the Wellness Centre at the Office of the Dean of Students. A copy will be marked to the student as well.\n
    
    The student should ensure that the attending doctor has indicated in his/ her medical file sufficient notes for the University Doctor to assess the student's medical situation. Submission of fake medical certificates will attract censure including termination of enrolment at the University.\n
    
    Absences due to illnesses without any treatment by an outside doctor or the University doctor will not be treated as Unavoidable Absence.\n
    
    In the case of a family tragedy, it is advisable that supporting documents be submitted to the Programme Chair along with an application for Unavoidable Absence. The same will not be granted for missing sessions due to religious reasons or social events including weddings in the family.\n
    
    All cases will be treated on their individual merits and demerits.\n
    
    If Unavoidable Absence is approved, the student's Programme Chair will convey this to all other Programme Chairs and Programme Managers.\n
    
    Note: This policy only changes the manner in which Grade drop applies in the case of Unavoidable Absence. A student is not marked present for sessions missed. \n
    Please see the details and process flow on these policies in AURIS. In case of any doubt, please consult the Programme Chair or the Programme Officer.
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What is the attendance policy when a course is added/dropped",
    answer: `Attendance policy when a Course is added during Add/ Drop Week:\n
    If a student adds a Course after the Semester begins then the percentage of attendance will be calculated with respect to the number of sessions in the Course after the student has added it.\n
    Any grievance with regards to application of the Attendance Policy can be addressed to the Course Instructor, the Programme Chair, the Associate Dean, and the Dean.
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What co-curricular activities are included at Ahmedabad university",
    answer: `We believe that our students by engaging both, with the curricular as well as co-curricular programmes. Co- curricular programmes build attributes of success in your profession, in life skills, and in perspectives that help understand the environment that we live in and work with, better. There are various opportunities to participate in existing programmes or develop one with the support of the Schools and the Dean of Students.\n\n

  Independent Study Period \n
   
  The Independent Study Period or ISP is a mini term in December where students do activities and courses that are not a part of the regular semester. This course ranges from specially curated ISP courses, apprenticing with a faculty on his/her research project or an independent research project developed by the student and supervised by a faculty. Students earn credits for this work and they may be counted towards the GERs, Free Electives or even Major Electives. Some students take an ISP simply because they want to participate in this highly creativity oriented and reflective activity. The specially curated ISP courses are a unique experience and are conducted in a studio mode. The student undergoes this course one at a time over a two-week period. These courses are around a passion, are interdisciplinary in nature, are experiential and project based, and build conceptual knowledge. ISP ends with an Expo where all courses display their work to the University community and the public. Students often have diverse passions but no means to explore them, especially when those passions are not related to their academic specializations. The ISP is an opportunity to explore these interests beyond the classroom, making learning very hands on, collaborative and intimate. Classrooms turn into studios and thinking out of the box is replaced with reimagining the box. These courses are offered in an 8-hour day format on 15 consecutive days, enabling concentrated learning for students through block courses, studio-inspired experiential courses, perspective, skill building, field courses and innovative experiments in learning. ISP is an amazingly creative period on the campus and truly embodies the Ahmedabad learning spirit.\n\n
  
  The Nalanda\n
  The Nalanda is a highly sought after, student-centered programme that provides students an opportunity to engage in a small group with deep thinkers of our times. This is an antidote to large lectures by building independent thinking and dialogue as a mode of enquiry. Every alternate week, The Nalanda invites a deep thinker to announce a topic of conversation and invites students to engage in a dialogue. The rules of The Nalanda require each student, who signs up to participate, to read and reflect on the topic of the conversation and come to the evening with a question in mind. Students occupy the central position and all others sit in the periphery.Students have the prerogative of engagement with the speaker. The event ends with a dinner with all participants, where the conversation spills over into deeper discussions. A list of past speakers at Nalanda can be found on our website.\n\n
   
  Undergraduate Research Programme\n
  Through our Undergraduate Research Programme or UGRP, students have an opportunity to extensively explore a particular issue or idea through a research project. You have the option of working on an independent project or under the supervision of a professor or alongside a faculty member, assisting in their lab work and research project. State-of-the-art laboratory facilities are made available to senior undergraduate students so that they are exposed to using sophisticated equipment at an early stage in their academic life, making them better prepared for graduate school and a research-oriented career.\n\n
  
  The Conversation series\n
  A flagship event of the Amrut Mody School of Management, The Conversation Series is a series of webinars cultivating unique interdisciplinary dialogue on issues related to management, economics, and public policy between a distinguished person from academia/industry/public policy/media and an in-house faculty of Ahmedabad University. Through The Conversation Series, the University seeks to understand the implications of past and current events on the future and drive collaborative research and consulting opportunities. It also presents an opportunity for the audience and the speaker to develop engaging professional relationships.\n\n
   
  Volunteerism: Engaging with the Community\n
  Volunteerism is a semester-long engagement with the community we live in. It enables you to become a conscious member of the society who is aware and concerned about the pressing issues we face in our lives and strives to find solutions. This will be done through a mandatory course, 'Engagement with the Community', which is a graduation requirement. This course can be taken anytime during the stay at the University, but it is advised that you engage with this course during the first two years. It is offered in many forms and will be offered on a Pass/Fail basis. One of its objectives is to sensitize students to the realities of the less privileged, and to encourage them to contribute effort and action in social service with empathy and kindness, to learn to look beyond self, and to be inclusive in thought throughout your lives.\n\n
   
  Campus-wide and School-wide Seminar Series\n
  Seminars by experts are organized on the Campus practically every day of the week. Some are research seminars organized by Schools and Centres where experts in diverse disciplines speak about their research. Others are public seminars that are aimed at the public understanding of different disciplines and current issues in those areas. You must engage with these highly cutting-edge debates on current issues or significant findings. Posters announcing these seminars are put up throughout the Campus, on the University's social media handles, and on our mobile app, ICE. This is a great opportunity to engage with highly regarded scholars from around the world.\n\n
   
  Chiasma\n
  Started in 2017, Chiasma, by the School of Arts and Sciences, Ahmedabad University, is a science fest organized by the students and for the students. The fest roots the motto of "Motivating Curiosity and promotes the idea of research amongst the youth. Literally, as Chiasma links together the two arms of chromosomes, the event is also a cross of science and culture, learning and fun. Scientific workshops during the day catering to the fundamental foundations of the fest are followed by cultural celebrations in the evenings.\n\n
     
  Ingenium\n
  Ingenium is the annual technology festival of Ahmedabad University. Started in 2016, Ingenium celebrates the spirit of innovation and engineering solutions, hosting a wide array of competitions and workshops. It applies the University's core values of Project Based Learning and Multidisciplinary Approach to real-life problems.\n\n
   
  Concourse\n
  Concourse is an Annual Festival of the Management School that provides students of Ahmedabad University an opportunity to participate in various business simulations, learn to start new ventures, pick up critical skills on how to become a professional, and engage thoughtfully with leaders from business and society.\n
   `
  },
  {
    question: "Independent Study Period",
    answer: "The Independent Study Period or ISP is a mini term in December where students do activities and courses that are not a part of the regular semester. This course ranges from specially curated ISP courses, apprenticing with a faculty on his/her research project or an independent research project developed by the student and supervised by a faculty. Students earn credits for this work and they may be counted towards the GERs, Free Electives or even Major Electives. Some students take an ISP simply because they want to participate in this highly ﻿creativity oriented and reflective activity. The specially curated ISP courses are a unique experience and are conducted in a studio mode. The student undergoes this course one at a time over a two-week period. These courses are around a passion, are interdisciplinary in nature, are experiential and project based, and build conceptual knowledge. ISP ends with an Expo where all courses display their work to the University community and the public. Students often have diverse passions but no means to explore them, especially when those passions are not related to their academic specializations. The ISP is an opportunity to explore these interests beyond the classroom, making learning very hands on, collaborative and intimate. Classrooms turn into studios and thinking out of the box is replaced with reimagining the box. These courses are offered in an 8-hour day format on 15 consecutive days, enabling concentrated learning for students through block courses, studio-inspired experiential courses, perspective, skill building, field courses and innovative experiments in learning. ISP is an amazingly creative period on the campus and truly embodies the Ahmedabad learning spirit."
  },
  {
    question: "The Nalanda",
    answer: "The Nalanda is a highly sought after, student-centered programme that provides students an opportunity to engage in a small group with deep thinkers of our times. This is an antidote to large lectures by building independent thinking and dialogue as a mode of enquiry. Every alternate week, The Nalanda invites a deep thinker to announce a topic of conversation and invites students to engage in a dialogue. The rules of The Nalanda require each student, who signs up to participate, to read and reflect on the topic of the conversation and come to the evening with a question in mind. Students occupy the central position and all others sit in the periphery. Students have the prerogative of engagement with the speaker. The event ends with a dinner with all participants, where the conversation spills over into deeper discussions. A list of past speakers at Nalanda can be found on our website."
  },
  {
    question: "Undergraduate Research Programme",
    answer: "Through our Undergraduate Research Programme or UGRP, students have an opportunity to extensively explore a particular issue or idea through a research project. You have the option of working on an independent project or under the supervision of a professor or alongside a faculty member, assisting in their lab work and research project. State-of-the-art laboratory facilities are made available to senior undergraduate students so that they are exposed to using sophisticated equipment at an early stage in their academic life, making them better prepared for graduate school and a research-oriented career."
  },
  {
    question: "The Conversation series",
    answer: "A flagship event of the Amrut Mody School of Management, The Conversation Series is a series of webinars cultivating unique interdisciplinary dialogue on issues related to management, economics, and public policy between a distinguished person from academia/industry/public policy/media and an in-house faculty of Ahmedabad University. Through The Conversation Series, the University seeks to understand the implications of past and current events on the future and drive collaborative research and consulting opportunities. It also presents an opportunity for the audience and the speaker to develop engaging professional relationships."
  },
  {
    question: "Volunteerism",
    answer: "Volunteerism is a semester-long engagement with the community we live in. It enables you to become a conscious member of the society who is aware and concerned about the pressing issues we face in our lives and strives to find solutions. This will be done through a mandatory course, 'Engagement with the Community', which is a graduation requirement. This course can be taken anytime during the stay at the University, but it is advised that you engage with this course during the first two years. It is offered in many forms and will be offered on a Pass/Fail basis. One of its objectives is to sensitize students to the realities of the less privileged, and to encourage them to contribute effort and action in social service with empathy and kindness, to learn to look beyond self, and to be inclusive in thought throughout your lives."
  },
  {
    question: "Campus wide and School-wide Seminar Series",
    answer: "Seminars by experts are organized on the Campus practically every day of the week. Some are research seminars organized by Schools and Centres where experts in diverse disciplines speak about their research. Others are public seminars that are aimed at the public understanding of different disciplines and current issues in those areas. You must engage with these highly cutting-edge debates on current issues or significant findings. Posters announcing these seminars are put up throughout the Campus, on the University's social media handles, and on our mobile app, ICE. This is a great opportunity to engage with highly regarded scholars from around the world."
  },
  {
    question: "Chiasma",
    answer: "Started in 2017, Chiasma, by the School of Arts and Sciences, Ahmedabad University, is a science fest organized by the students and for the students. The fest roots the motto of 'Motivating Curiosity' and promotes the idea of research amongst the youth. Literally, as Chiasma links together the two arms of chromosomes, the event is also a cross of science and culture, learning and fun. Scientific workshops during the day catering to the fundamental foundations of the fest are followed by cultural celebrations in the evenings."
  },
  {
    question: "Ingenium",
    answer: "Ingenium is the annual technology festival of Ahmedabad University. Started in 2016, Ingenium celebrates the spirit of innovation and engineering solutions, hosting a wide array of competitions and workshops. It applies the University's core values of Project Based Learning and Multidisciplinary Approach to real-life problems."
  },
  {
    question: "Concourse",
    answer: "Concourse is an Annual Festival of the Management School that provides students of Ahmedabad University an opportunity to participate in various business simulations, learn to start new ventures, pick up critical skills on how to become a professional, and engage thoughtfully with leaders from business and society."
  },
  {
    question: "Can you change a program or a major",
    answer: "The eligibility requirements for changing or declaring a Major may include a minimum performance in relevant courses at the University and inclusion of certain subjects in the academic programme of the student in high school. Changing between Bachelor of Technology Majors, whose admission is regulated by the government, will be as per the relevant regulations. Changing to a Bachelor of Technology Major from a non-Bachelor of Technology Major will not be permitted because of Government of Gujarat regulations. Students will finalize their Major in the 4th registered semester (by the time of pre-registration of courses for the 5th registered semester). This does not preclude a student from changing the Major at any time so long as the statutory limit (of 10 years) of completing an undergraduate programme is adhered to. Changing a Major or entering the University with an Undeclared Major, can, in some cases, lead to a student taking longer than the normal duration to obtain the degree. Students should consult the Major Advisors or the Programme Chairs about changing or choosing a Major or a Programme. Please inquire about the eligibility requirements of different majors and programmes."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the procedure for withdrawal from the University For a Newly Admitted Student",
    answer: `For withdrawal of admission and seeking a refund of fees, the candidate is required to submit the original fee receipt, admission offer letter, and other documents received at the time of admission, and fill in the letter of request for withdrawal duly signed by the student/ applicant and the Parent/Guardian thereof.
    The letter of request for withdrawal is available at the Office of Admissions and Financial Aid and can be filled and submitted at the time of seeking withdrawal along with the required documents. \n\n
    Refund of Fees\n
    The refund of fees will be processed in accordance with the prevailing University Grants Commission (UGC) guidelines and provisions made on the Admissions webpage.
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What is the procedure for Withdrawal from the University For Students in the Bachelor of Technology Programme",
    answer: "The refund of fees will be processed in accordance with Admission Committee for Professional Courses (ACPC) guidelines as specified from time to time, within the time limit indicated by them. Fees shall be refunded after completion of the admission process, provided that the seat vacated by the student is filled by another candidate. The relevant refund amount will be processed after the University receives the withdrawal application and the refund shall be directly credited through NEFT/ RTGS to the bank account given by the applicant."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the procedure for Withdrawal from the University For an Existing Student",
    answer: `A student who has enrolled for courses at Ahmedabad University and wishes to withdraw his/ her admission is required to fill up the Application for Withdrawal of Admission available online in the Ahmedabad University Resource Information System (AURIS). The student needs to take a printout of the form and get it signed by the concerned personnel from the Programme Office for "No Dues" and submit it to the Programme Office between 9.00 am and 6.00 pm on any working day. The application will be processed within 15 working days from the date of receiving it. \n\n
    
    Refund of Fees\n
    The refund of fees will be processed in accordance with the University's refund policy. The refund of fees, if any, shall be directly credited through NEFT/ RTGS only to the bank account given by the applicant at the time of application. The deposit amount will be refunded after deducting the dues, if any.\n\n
    
    The refund of fees shall be made after deduction as per the following table:
    Percentage of Refund of Tuition Fees (including the point
    of time when the notice of withdrawal of admission is served to the Programme Office):\n
    
    90% - 30 days before the start of the academic session \
    50% - 15 days before the start of the academic session \
    NIL - After the academic session starts \n\n
    
    Please see the instruction on AURIS and discuss your withdrawal with the Programme Office that will guide you through this process.
    `
  },
  {
    question: "Visiting students",
    question: "Visiting Students are those who are not enrolled in our programmes and will not pass out from our University. Visiting students are naturally enrolled at another university and are either at Ahmedabad University for a short duration spanning a few weeks or to do a semester which spans a few months. Their presence and their interaction at the University may be for a few set credits or for a certification and shall not be entitled to a degree certificate from Ahmedabad University."
  },
  {
    question: "Administration and Facilities",
    answer: `University Administration\n
    The university administration comprises the following office and people, who will be able to help you navigate your journey of learning at ahmedabad. \n\n
    
    Pankaj Chandra\n
    Vice chancellor\n\n
    
    Manmeet Ahluwalia\n
    Director\n
    Communications\n\n
    
    Sanjay Banavar\n
    Director\n
    Libraries\n\n
    
    Juhi Bansal\n
    Senior Associate Director\n
    Centre for Learning Futures\n\n
    
    Sankarshan Basu\n
    Dean\n
    Amrut Mody School of Management\n\n
    
    Neel Kamal Chapagain\n
    Director\n
    Centre for Heritage Management\n\n
    
    Sanjay Chaudhar\n
    Dean of Students.\n
    Associate Dean\n
    School of Engineering and Applied Science\n\n
    
    Pratyush Chatteriee\n
    Director\n
    Office of Housing and Residential Life\n\n
    
    Ridul Deka \n
    Head of Operations\n\n
    
    Neha Desai\n
    Director\n
    Office of Alumni Affairs and Advancement\n\n
    
    Mohit Gupta\n
    Director\n
    Career Development Centre\n\n
    
    Mihir Jhaveri\n
    Chief Financial Office\n\n
    
    Pankaj Joshi\n
    Director\n
    International Centre for Space and Cosmology\n\n
    
    Tanvi Kapur\n
    Associate Director\n
    Communications and Design\n\n
    
    Vaibhav Kadia\n
    Assistant Dean of Students\n
    (Students Engagement)\n\n
    
    Sunil Kale\n
    Dean\n
    School of Engineering and Applied Science\n\n
    
    Ashwin Kumar\n
    Director\n
    Centre for Learning Futures\n\n
    
    Deepak Kunzru\n
    Dean\n
    Graduate School and Research\n\n
    
    Darshini Mahadevia\n
    Associate Dean, Arts\n
    School of Arts and Sciences\n\n
    
    Colonel Vinit Menon\n
    Director\n
    Campus Operations\n\n
    
    Tejaswini Niranjana\n
    Director, Centre for Inter-Asian\n
    Research\n
    Dean of Online Programmes\n\n
    
    Kalpana Pareek\n
    Assistant Dean, Wellness\n
    Counselor\n\n
    
    Parag Patel\n
    Senior Associate Dean\n
    Amrut Mody School of Management\n\n
    
    Saptam Patel\n
    Assistant Dean\n
    Undergraduate College\n\n
    
    Vikram Patel\n
    Associate Director\n\n
    Office of Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aid\n\n
    
    Balaji Prakash\n
    Associate Dean, Sciences\n
    School of Arts and Sciences\n\n
    
    Raghavan Rangarajan\n
    Dean\n
    School of Arts and Sciences\n\n
    
    Tanvi Shah Rangwala\n
    CEO\n
    VentureStudio\n
    
    Mehul Raval\n
    Associate Dean\n
    Experiential Learning\n\n
    
    Vishal Samal\n
    Associate Director\n\n
    
    Office of Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aid\n\n
    
    Parth Sarwate\n
    Director\n
    Office of Undergraduate\n
    Admissions and Financial Aid\n\n
    
    Monika Setia\n
    Senior Associate Director\n
    Office of International Affairs\n\n
    
    Bhupendra Shah\n
    Registrar\n\n
    
    Fenil Shah\n
    Director\n
    Ahmedabad Design Lab\n\n
    
    Vishal Shah\n
    Associate Director\n
    Career Development Centre\n\n
    
    Priyadarshi Shukla\n
    Director\n
    Global Centre for Environment and Energy\n\n
    
    Mita Suthar\n
    Controller of Examinations\n
    Assistant Academic Registrar\n\n
    
    Siddharth Swaminarayan\n
    Academic Registrar\n\n
    
    Vivek Tanavde\n
    Associate Dean\n
    Undergraduate College\n\n
    
    Devanath Tirupati\n
    Executive Provost.\n\n
    `
  },
  {
    question: "How is the University residence",
    answer: `University Residences provide secure spaces for Ahmedabad University students to live in a homelike environment vital for their growth and development. The University currently provides two high quality Residences in its commitment towards simple, comfortable and secure living for those from out of town. Our Residences are a lesson in building a community that has at its core a respect for diversity in ideas, in ways of living, in food preferences, in cultural practices, in language and in religion. While our own dorms are under construction, our University Residences are currently in partnership with an entrepreneurial student accommodation firm, Feels Like Home (FLH), and are overseen by a dedicated Office of Student Housing and Residential Life. The University has onsite Residence Managers/ Wardens to address any concerns that students might have. Our modern housing options offered for both boys and girls are within close proximity to the campus with a dedicated transportation facility to pick up and drop students to and from the Residences and the Campus at specified hours. Both Residences are under strict security monitoring. \n\n
    Location\n
    For Male Students\n
    Ahmedabad University Residence FLH2 Near Regional Passport Office, Gulbai Tekra, Navrangpura, Ahmedabad, Gujarat - 380009 (Distance from Central Campus: 1.2 km)\n\n\n
    
    For Female Students\n
    Ahmedabad University Residence FLH3 Near Sarovar Complex,\n
    Surajmal Zaveri Road, Navrangpura, Ahmedabad, Gujarat - 380009 (Distance from Central Campus: 850 m)\n\n
    The following services are provided\n
    • Choice of twin or triple sharing rooms with every student having a single bed with mattress, a wardrobe, a writing table, a chair and bed linen set\
• Air-conditioned room with a ceiling fan, window blinds, a bath mat and a dustbin\
• Attached bathrooms\
• Well-equipped gyms with adequate aerobic and strength-training equipment\
• TV rooms with popular OTT subscriptions and informal seating\
• Reading/study room\
• Dining and café areas with common facilities like microwave ovens and refrigerators\
• Electricity consumption chargeable only for the AC on actuals - as per the sub-meter in each room\
• Normal electricity consumption for fans, lights and geysers is part of the fees\n\n
University Residences are committed to ensuring a home- like experience with:\n
• Hygienic food: Nutritious and sumptuous vegetarian and non-vegetarian meals with ample variety.\
• Security: Biometric access systems and 24/7 CCTV surveillance.\
• Laundry: Free laundry with pick up and drop service for up to four clothes on a daily basis. In-house washing machines for personal/undergarments and ironing boards for delicate clothes.\
• High-speed internet: Wi-Fi enabled high-speed internet access with IT support services.\
• Housekeeping: Professional housekeeping of rooms and common areas every day.\
• Medical assistance: First-aid kits with a doctor-on-call facility.\
• Emergency management: Presence of a robust\
emergency management system in case of any natural disaster.\
•No smoking: Strictly no smoking allowed inside the Residences.\n\n

For more details on the University Residences, please email director.studentresidences@ahduni.edu.in or contact us at +91.9910073125
`
  },
  {
    question: "What is The Arboretum",
    answer: "The Arboretum (or the Arb) is being built as the green lung of the city of Ahmedabad. It comprises nearly 100 species of trees that create a unique ecosystem of sustainable development on the campus when added to the existing trees within the campuses. We plan to plant close to 800 trees in a 1.12 lakh sq. ft. area (most of which has already been done) and hope to bring birds and local flora back to the city. It reflects our aspirations for the ecology of the campus and contains outdoor spaces for classes and conversations, a step well that doubles as an open air theater, and many spaces for curated outdoor activities. Situated in the heart of the Central Campus, it also provides a quiet place for reflection, a conversational walk with a student or a colleague, a place to remain undisturbed, and a place to rest under shaded groves."
  },
  {
    question: "Where are University Grounds",
    answer: `The University has several grounds/newly built sports facilities to promote sports, games, and related activities on its Campus.\n
    The following facilities can be reserved and used:\
    North Ground\
    South Ground Central Lawns\
    HL Ground\
    AES Sports Facility\
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What are Sports room details",
    answer: "New building, AMSOM, UG Campus GICT - Room no, B07, Student recreation, University Center"
  },
  {
    question: "Where are grounds for specific sports",
    answer:  `Format: Sports | Ground\n
              Chess | HL Pavilion (Indoor), AMSOM East Campus\n
              Table Tennis | HL Pavilion (Indoor), AMSOM East Campus & BO7, Basement, Students Recreation Room, GICT Central Campus & 4" floor, University Centre\n
              Badminton | SCS (Outdoor) & 2nd floor (MPH), University Centre\n
              Basketball | 2ndfloor (MPH), University Centre & AES Sports Complex & Near HL pavilion (Basketball ground)\n
              Volleyball | AES Sports Complex & Near Bionest Gate no. 6\n
              Kabaddi | AES Sports Complex & GICT ground, Central Campus\n
              Cricket | AES Sports Complex & HL Pavilion Cricket Ground\n
              Football | AES Football Ground, Plot 705 & Football Ground, GICT Central Campus\n
              Squash | 3rd Floor, University Centre \n
              Futsal Court | Terrace, University Centre\n
              Athletics (Running Track) | Terrace, University Centre\n
              Gymnasium | 4h floor, University Centre
    `
  },
  {
    question: "Where are university libraries and its working",
    answer: `The library at Ahmedabad University is rapidly emerging as one of the country's leading academic and research libraries. The University Library System consists of a central library and two reading rooms, one each at the Amrut Mody School of Management and the School of Arts and Sciences. The University library has a diverse collection of print and online resources. It includes books, periodicals, newspapers, theses/ dissertations, project reports, bound volumes, case studies, online databases, and multimedia resources. The collection supports a multidisciplinary and like curriculum research requirements that covers subjects Engineering, Computer Science, Mathematics, Humanities, Management, Biological Sciences, and Social Sciences\n
    Books Borrowing Facility\
      - Students (other than PhD Scholars) are eligible to borrow two books for fourteen days, whereas PhD Scholars are eligible to borrow ten books for one month. The library collects late fees at Rs 5/- per day for the first 15 days and the sixteenth day onwards at Rs 10/- per day for overdue books.\n\n
    Digital Initiatives\
      - University Library System (ULS) Library Online Catalogue: \n
        - All the campus libraries have a user-friendly Online Public Access Catalogue (OPAC) that allows members to check the availability of a book, renew borrowed books, reserve issued books, and see their transaction history.\n\n
      - Remote Xs:\n
        - Remote Xs enables users to access the library  subscribed online resources outside the campus.\n\n
      - Discovery Services\n
        - The ProQuest Summon. Summon discovery service is a single search window where users can connect to vital research resources in one go.\n\n
      Central Library Working Hours\
        The Central Library is open from 8:00 am to 10:00 pm during the Semester and Vacation periods, and on all weekdays. It is open from 9:00 am to 5:00 pm on Saturdays and Sundays. Library users can borrow/return books from 9:00 am to 9:00 pm on all weekdays and from 9:00 am to 5:00 pm on Saturdays and Sundays. During examinations, it is open from 8:00 am till 12:00 am (midnight). The two reading rooms are open from 9:00 am to 6:00 pm on all weekdays only for reference. The library remains closed on declared holidays.\n
        Format: TYPES OF RESOURCES | NUMBERS\n
              Book Titles | 34780\
              Books' Volume | 4535\
              E-Books | 222462+ \
              Journals, Magazines and Newspapers | 125 \
              Online Journals | 6896+ \
              Self-Study CDs | 3614 \
              Other learning material: (Bound Volumes and Thesis and Dissertations) | 924 \n\n
      Institutional Repository\n
        Institutional Repository (Dspace) is a platform to access all institutional reference resources, old question papers, faculty publications, and student theses and dissertations.\n\n
      Grammarly\n
        Grammarly allows users to customize their style, tone, and context-specific language.\n\n
      EndNote\n
        EndNote is a commercial reference management software that manages bibliographies and references of the users.
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What are the Digital Resources at the Libraries",
    answer: `Digital Resources can be accessed using the University network system. Information on them and how to access them is available on the library webpage.\n
    Full-Text Databases\n
      - ACM Digital Library (49 e-Journals)\
      - APA PsycArticles (86 Journals)\
      - American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) (33 Journals)\
      - American Institute of Physics (AIP) - eSS Collection (19 Journals)\
      - Cambridge University Press (17 Journals)\
      - EBSCO Business Source Elite (512 Journals)\
      - IEEE Xplore Digital Library (375 e-Journals) JSTOR (3888 e-Journals)\
      - Oxford University Press HSS Collection (204 Journals)\
      - Project Euclid Premium Collection (46 Journals)\
      - Project Muse Premium Collection (687 Journals) Science Direct (974 Journals)\n\n
    
    E-Books\n
      - ProQuest E-Books Central (2,18,905+ E-Books)\
      - Springer Computer Science E-Books with LNCS (3557+ E-Books)\
    
    Statistical Databases\n
      - ACE Equity V2\
      - Consumer Pyramids dx\
      - Economic\
      - EPWRF\
      - India Stat\
      - Outlook\
      - Industry Outlook Prowess\
      - State of India Tracxn\n\n

    Bibliographic Database\n
      - Scopus \n\n
    
    Standards\n
      - BIS Standards\n\n
    
    Services\n
      - Alumni Membership Circulation Services Discovery Service\
      - Document Delivery Service (DDS) HBR Case study procurement Information Literacy Programmes Inter-Library Loan (ILL) New Arrivals Alerts\
      - Newspaper Display Plagiarism Check Service\
      - Old Question Papers archival Reference Services\
      - Table of Content (TOC) service\n\n
    
  Apart from these, the University Library System also frequently organizes various events and activities to develop the reading habit among its students\n\n
      
  Institutional Membership\n
    The library also has Institutional Membership in the following organisations\
      - Association of Management Development Institutions in South Asia (AMDISA)\
      - CEPT University\
      - Current Science\
      - DELNET\
      - Central Library at Indian Institute of Technology, Gandhinagar\
      - INFLIBNET\
      - Vikram Sarabhai Library at IIMA
  `
  },
  {
    question: "What are  the Facilities at library",
    answer: `Air-conditioned Reading Rooms\
    Creativity Hub\
    E-hub to access online resources\
    E-hub for the Visually Impaired\
    E-mail & SMS Alert\
    Kiosk (Access to Online Catalogue)\
    Library extended hours during examinations \
    Reading Cubicles\
    Reading Rooms with Wi-Fi facility\
    Remote Access\
    RFID (Self check-out and check-in)\
    Screening of Swayam Prabha Channel
    `
  },
  {
    question: "How is  Campus IT Network, Technology Support and Instructional Technology",
    answer: `
    We deploy and support technology solutions that enable faculty, students, staff and associates to enhance their teaching, learning, research, work and service experience. We use technology to drive efficiency, support innovation in teaching, research and digital technology to transform our learning environment. 
    Students at the University have access to various technology resources. Wired as well as wireless network connections are provided across the University, including a high-speed internet connectivity across the Campus. The high-speed internet access is provided centrally through a firewall. The Wi-Fi network is an advanced controller-based system with wireless access points distributed across the Campus covering classrooms, labs, meeting rooms, library, canteen, etc.
    Classrooms and labs have LAN and Wi-Fi connectivity. There are dedicated computer labs for students' use as well, though we strongly encourage everyone to bring their own devices. Each library is equipped with computer resources. Our campus is covered with CCTV to ensure safety and security. Students at Ahmedabad University are provided individual email IDs with a storage quota limit of 10 GB on the University domain (i.e. username@ahduni.edu.in). Similarly, alumni also have access to their emails with a storage limit of 1 GB.
    Various email groups are also created for ease of communication and to share necessary information across various Schools of the University. In addition to the above infrastructure, the University uses KOHA for Library Management and Moodle as the Learning Management System. The University provides plagiarism check services to all its users through the renowned software Turnitin. Enterprise level endpoint security from eScan is deployed for all computer systems across the University and it is also made available to students for installation (1 device per student).
    We actively promote use of open source software and licensed software at the University. We discourage the use of unlicensed software on the Campus. Online subscriptions for various software are available including MATLAB, AutoCAD,Turnitin, Cadence, National Instruments LabVIEW, Solid Works, ANSYS, LaserVCAD CNC train, etc. The occupancy of laboratories with higher-end software is planned for the benefit of students in such a way so as to provide the best availability and utilization. Students also use various open source softwares and application platforms like Ubuntu, OpenOffice, Audacity, Wireshark, Hadoop, Python, MAESTRO element, Chem Doodle, PHP, and Active Perl, and are encouraged to try other open source softwares.\n
    Web Resources Links:\n
    Ahmedabad University Resource Information System (AURIS): https://auris.ahduni.edu.in \
    Learning Management System (LMS): http://lms.ahduni.edu.in \
    University Library System (ULS): http://uls.ahduni.edu.in\
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What is Moodle: Our Learning Management System (LMS)",
    answer:`Apart from several digital initiatives at Ahmedabad University, Moodle Learning Management System (LMS) is widely used to enhance learning. LMS is a web-based Learning Management System which can be accessed from any device at any location where internet connectivity is available. At Ahmedabad University, you can use LMS to \n
      - Download course materials,\
      - Learn and participate in class discussions via forums, Follow a hyperlink to visit some external website and web pages,\
      - Submit an assignment to a drop box, take an in class quiz, or a quiz from home,\
      - View current grades and comments from faculty as the course progress,\
      - Watch a video that is embedded in LMS,\
      - Submit feedback, and much more.\n
    
    A quick way to get to your LMS courses is by going to this URL https://lms.ahduni.edu.in, click on login using the University email ID, and browse through your material and assignments. Students can use any internet enabled device to access the LMS. Every student, once enrolled in a course in LMS, will have access to the learning and reference material.    
    You can reach out to lms@ahduni.edu.in, mentioning your details like Student ID, emailƽ and exact query. You can expect a reply to your concerns in one working hour by one of our team members. For better visibility and appearance, use of the latest version of the internet browser is a must. Certain functions in LMS depend on browser plugǔĕns. You must have the following plugins/ add-ons enabled in your browser - Java, Adobe Flash Player, Adobe Readers and supported media player. Please visit IT Support or Moodle Support for any help.
    `
  },
  {
    question: "What is Ahmedabad University Resource Information System (AURIS)",
    answer: `
    Ahmedabad University Resource Information System or AURIS is a multipurpose, internet based platform for accessing and transacting a large number of administrative tasks and many academic requests at the University. AURIS allows you to communicate with the University administration, access University related information like policies, seminars or talks, register for courses, track your attendance, obtain scores and grades across courses, and more. Once your Ahmedabad email address is activated, you will get access to the AURIS portal. Unless specified, all course registrations will happen through the portal.
    Once your Ahmedabad email address is activated, you will get access to the AURIS portal. Unless specified, all course registrations will happen through the portal.
    For any troubleshooting about Wi-Fi, email, or AURIS portal connection, contact the School-level IT support staff or email: support.auris@ahduni.edu.in\n\n

   Communication through emails:\n
   Check your official University email ID on a regular basis, at least once every 24 hours. All notices, circulars, guidelines, and instructions will be circulated through this ID or LMS/ Moodle. You should track, read, and understand all such communication carefully.\n\n
  
   Readings for each course:\n
   You will receive detailed session plans for each course. Please read and understand these plans carefully and ensure you meet the requirements mentioned in it, including any assigned readings for the session. We expect you to have completed the readings ahead of the class.\n\n

   AURIS also provides the Ahmedabad University Telephone Directory.
`
  },
  {
    question: "What is ahmedabad university bookstore and where is it",
    answer: "The Ahmedabad University Bookstore is an academic one that serves the interests and needs of the students, faculty, staff and all its stakeholders. The Bookstore keeps material that is advanced in its treatment and supports deep inquiry of individuals and groups including young adults. It supports, through its material, research efforts of individuals. It holds material that is scholarly and purports to attract readers nationally and internationally. It is a knowledge center for the city and the country, a facility where all can access resources that are generally not available in common bookstores. The Bookstore retails textbooks as well as Ahmedabad University Merchandise. It organizes scholarly activities centered on books for the advancement of ideas and their application."
  },
  {
    question: "Where is the Reprographics Center and what does it do",
    answer: `The Reprographics Centre at Ahmedabad University is the in- house print room and documentation facility dedicated to fulfilling the needs of the students and administrative staff. Additionally, the Centre compiles and publishes courseware by way of academic course-packs and other print material for all the units of the University. It is the 'go to' resource for students when they need to put together quality documentation for their project and assignment submissions.\n
    Currently, the Centre offers the following services:\
      - Print on Demand (Black & White/ Colour)\
      - Copy on Demand (Black & White/ Colour)\
      - Document Scanning\
      - Spiral Binding Lamination\n
    
    The Centre is now housed in a new facility in Room #102 (above the cafeteria) at the University Centre. Operating hours for the Centre are 10:00 AM to 6:00 PM (Monday - Friday).
    `
  }
];